Guide to the Center for Death Penalty Litigation Records, 1953-2020; 1953-ongoing and undated RL.00199
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Case Files Series, 1969-2006, 115 boxes
  - Joseph Timothy Keel, 1986-2003, 26 boxes
    - Older correspondence (Box 52)
    - Criminal record check (Box 52)
    - Prior convictions (Box 52)
    - DNA (Box 52)
    - Witness list (Box 52)
    - Victor Matthew Keel - medical examiner's report (Box 52)
    - Motion for life sentence (Box 52)
    - Petition for writ of certiorari (Box 52)
    - DOC health files (Box 52)
    - Court documents, 2 folders (Box 52)
    - Mental health files
      - Mental retardation law (Box 52)
      - Beta test information (Box 52)
      - Dr.'s testimony (Box 52)
      - Neuropsych evaluation (Box 52)
      - Psych evaluation (Box 52)
      - Doctor's file (Box 52)
    - USSC - appendix to petition for writ of certiorari, volume II (Box 53)
    - Doctor's file (Box 53)
    - Court documents - Victor Matthew Keel case, 2 folders (Box 53)
    - Daily Southerner, 1987-1991 (Box 53)
    - Keel file index (Box 53)
    - MAR, 12/21/1995 (Box 53)
    - Attorney's notes (Box 53)
    - Transcript digest (Box 53)
    - Memoranda (Box 53)
    - Sentencing (Box 53)
    - Sentencing transcript, 10/30/1995 (Box 53)
    - Correspondence - trial counsel (Box 53)
    - Order procedurally barring MAR, 1/18/1996 (Box 53)
    - Petitioner's 4th circuit brief (Box 53)
    - North Carolina Supreme Court (NCSC) State v. Keel, 12/1992 (Box 53)
    - State's response to habeas petition (Box 53)
    - Habeas petition, 1/29/1996 (Box 53)
    - NCSC petition for writ of certiorari (Box 53)
    - Stay of execution order granted, 7/13/1995 (Box 53)
    - Judgment of death, 11/27/1995 (Box 53)
    - Cert petition and motion for stay of execution, 12/21/1995 (Box 53)
    - Motion for stay of execution - district court, 12/21/1995 (Box 53)
    - Order granting stay (draft), 12/1995 (Box 53)
    - State's response to motion for stay of execution, 12/22/1995 (Box 53)
    - Motion for clarification of order, 1/17/1996 (Box 53)
    - State's motion to procedurally bar MAR, 1/3/1996 (Box 53)
    - Appointment of counsel (Box 53)
    - Keel's releases (Box 53)
    - Orders re: stays (Box 54)
    - NCSC brief for state, 2/7/1994 (Box 54)
    - NCSC record on appeal, 10/20/1993 (Box 54)
    - NCSC defendant/appellant brief (Box 54)
    - USSC petition for writ of certiorari, 1/27/1995 (Box 54)
    - USSC petition for writ of certiorari, 2/1/1995 (Box 54)
    - USSC extension for writ, 12/1/1994 (Box 54)
    - USSC extension of time (Box 54)
    - Order setting date of execution, 6/24/1999 (Box 54)
    - Motion requesting NCSC relief, 7/16/1999 (Box 54)
    - Order denying relief, 7/1999 (Box 54)
    - DOC file (Box 54)
    - Jury selections (Box 54)
    - Pre-trial motions (Box 54)
    - Sample opening statements (Box 54)
    - Defendant's cross (Box 54)
    - Charge to jury (Box 54)
    - Newspaper clippings, 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Case law (Box 54)
    - Biographical information (Box 54)
    - Motion to continue, 1991 (Box 55)
    - Pre-trial motions, 1991 (Box 55)
    - Request for discovery, 1991 (Box 55)
    - NCSC ruling, 1992 (Box 55)
    - NCSC state brief, 9/2/1992 (Box 55)
    - Motions, 1993, 2 folders (Box 55)
    - NCSC ruling, 1994 (Box 55)
    - NCSC brief for state, 1994 (Box 55)
    - Issues and recommendations, 1993 (Box 55)
    - USSC application for extension of time, 12/1994 (Box 55)
    - NCSC certiorari petition, 1994 (Box 55)
    - Motion for appointment of counsel, 1995 (Box 55)
    - NCSC order dismissing petition for supersedeas, 1995 (Box 55)
    - Stay of execution, 1995 (Box 55)
    - Samples - federal appeals on habeas corpus (Box 55)
    - Petition for certiorari/supersedeas and motion for stay of execution, 1995 (Box 55)
    - Motion for stay of execution, 1995 (Box 55)
    - State's motion for summary judgment of petition for habeas corpus, 1996 (Box 55)
    - Affidavit in support of in forma pauperis, 1/29/1996 (Box 55)
    - USSC - state's response to defendant's petition for certiorari, 1/9/1996 (Box 55)
    - Order denying motion for clarification, 1996 (Box 55)
    - NCSC orders denying certiorari petition, 12/27/1995 (Box 55)
    - Motion to suspend page limitation, 2/9/1996 (Box 55)
    - State's response to N.C. District Court petition for habeas corpus, 2/15/1996 (Box 55)
    - State's response to habeas petition (Box 55)
    - Motion to extend time, 4/9/1996 (Box 55)
    - Order granting motion to extend time, 4/10/1996 (Box 55)
    - NCSC certiorari petition - writ of mandamus, 5/9/1996 (Box 55)
    - State's motion to give notice of exhaustion of all claims, 5/13/1996 (Box 55)
    - State's response to writ of certiorari and writ of mandamus, 5/13/1996 (Box 55)
    - Order denying writ of ceritorari and writ of mandamus, 7/30/1996 (Box 55)
    - Application to extend time to file USSC writ of certiorari, 10/16/1996 (Box 55)
    - Correspondence regarding USSC writ of certiorari, 1996-1997 (Box 55)
    - N.C. District Court petition for habeas corpus, 1996-1997 (Box 55)
    - State response to habeas appeal to USSC, 2/1996 (Box 55)
    - Attorney's motion to withdraw as counsel, 10/15/1996 (Box 55)
    - Records, 2002-2003 (Box 55)
    - State's motion to amend order, 12/1997 (Box 56)
    - N.C. District Court notice of appeal, 3/2/1998 (Box 56)
    - Appeal for certificate of probable cause, 5/14/1998 (Box 56)
    - Motion to file brief out of time, 4/1998 (Box 56)
    - Application for certificate of appealability and draft, 4/1998 (Box 56)
    - Petition for writ of certiorari, 1/2/1997 (Box 56)
    - Order for certificate of appealability, 4/30/1998 (Box 56)
    - 4th Circuit appeal - state's brief, 5/8/1998 (Box 56)
    - Reply brief of defendant, 5/20/1998 (Box 56)
    - State's additional authority, 9/2/1998 (Box 56)
    - Habeas corpus petition and appeals files (Box 56)
    - Motion for discovery - additional authority, 7/1998 (Box 56)
    - State's response to motion for discovery, 5/11/1998 (Box 56)
    - Notice of change of address, 12/4/1998 (Box 56)
    - Memorandum regarding additional authority, 8/1999 (Box 56)
    - Keel v. French chronology (Box 56)
    - Motion for discovery, 5/1998 (Box 56)
    - Transcript of hearing, 9/3/1999 (Box 56)
    - Petition for writ of certiorari, 2/26/2003 (Box 56)
    - Memorandum opinion and final order, 1/27/2003 (Box 56)
    - Notice of appeal, 3/23/1987 (Box 56)
    - MAR, 4/6/1987 (Box 56)
    - Attorney fees, 1987 case (Box 56)
    - 1987 case court documents (Box 56)
    - Motion for imposition of life sentence, 1/31/2002 (Box 56)
    - Legal correspondence, 1/2003 (Box 56)
    - Court response to motions, 10/16/2002 (Box 56)
    - Second motion to stay retardation hearing, 10/7/2002 (Box 56)
    - Petition for writ of certiorari, 3/28/2003 (Box 56)
    - Production of records correspondence, 2 folders (Box 56)
    - Affidavit of E.H. (Box 56)
    - 1987 transcript digest (Box 56)
    - Authorization for expert witnesses (Box 57)
    - Order appointing counsel, 12/12/2000 (Box 57)
    - 4th Circuit oral argument notes, 2 folders (Box 57)
    - Transcript of Edgecombe County Court, 12/12/2000 (Box 57)
    - Transcript of Edgecombe County Court, 9/21/2001 (Box 57)
    - Ex parte motion to allow transportation, 7/1999 (Box 57)
    - Petition for writ of supersedeas and motion for temporary stay, 9/27/1999 (Box 57)
    - Memorandum of additional information to state's petition for writ of prohibition, 7/1999, 2 folders (Box 57)
    - NCSC order denying writ of certiorari, 8/19/1999 (Box 57)
    - Additional info to defendant's response to writ of prohibition, 8/2/1999 (Box 57)
    - Defendant's response to writ of prohibition, 8/1999, 2 folders (Box 57)
    - Order setting date of execution, 9/2/1999 (Box 57)
    - State's motion to vacate, 9/1/1999, 3 folders (Box 57)
    - DOC warden's reply to Keel's response, 9/6/1999 (Box 57)
    - State's motion for court to make findings of fact and conclusions of law, 9/20/1999 (Box 57)
    - Transcript of 9/22/1999 (Box 57)
    - Petition for writs of prohibition, mandus, certiorari, 9/27/1999 (Box 57)
    - Interview files (Box 58)
    - Mental health documents (Box 58)
    - Motion to stay, 10/3/2002 (Box 58)
    - Exhibits, 1999-2001 (Box 58)
    - Judgment and commitment, 1987 (Box 58)
    - Request for stay of execution, 7/26/1999 (Box 58)
    - Affidavit of JHF, 1986 (Box 58)
    - Judgment, 1986 (Box 58)
    - Notice of appeal, 1986 (Box 58)
    - Discovery, 1991 (Box 58)
    - Motion to support defendant's statements, 4/18/1991 (Box 58)
    - 4th Circuit documents, 1998 (Box 58)
    - NCSC documents, 1999-2001 (Box 58)
    - State's bench brief, 12/12/2000 (Box 58)
    - Mental retardation documents (Box 58)
    - DOC visitation information (Box 58)
    - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 58)
    - Press, 1999 (Box 58)
    - Lift of stay of execution, 9/2003 (Box 58)
    - Transcript excerpts (Box 58)
    - NCSC petition for writ of certiorari, 2/1995 (Box 58)
    - Clemency (Box 58)
    - Writ of certiorari, 2003 (Box 58)
    - Exhibits, 2 folders (Box 59)
    - Issues - verdict (Box 59)
    - State's answer to jury determination of death penalty, 9/10/2002 (Box 59)
    - Transcript, certified 8/30/2002 (Box 59)
    - State's answer to defendant's second MAR, 4/16/2002 (Box 59)
    - DOC file (Box 59)
    - Memo opinion and final order, 1/27/2003 (Box 59)
    - Defense exhibits (Box 59)
    - Defense exhibits and notes, 2 folders (Box 59)
    - Trial transcript - volume I, 10/7/2002 (Box 59)
    - DOC disciplinary records (Box 59)
    - DOC files (Box 60)
    - Defense exhibits (Box 60)
    - Press clippings (Box 60)
    - Correspondence, 5 folders (Box 60)
    - Correspondence, 4 folders (Box 61)
    - Medical records, 3 folders (Box 61)
    - Certified copies of judgment, 1986 (Box 61)
    - Discovery documents (Box 61)
    - Pictures and certificates (Box 61)
    - Photo of Keel family (Box 61)
    - School records (Box 61)
    - Medical records summaries (Box 61)
    - United Nations correspondence (Box 61)
    - Affidavits (Box 62)
      - Sallenger affidavit (Box 62)
      - K.R. affidavit (Box 62)
      - S.B. affidavit (Box 62)
    - Mental health
      - Medical records and notes, 2 folders (Box 62)
      - Mental health documents (Box 62)
      - N.C. DOC medical records (Box 62)
      - DOC psychiatric evaluation, 5/6/1987 (Box 62)
      - N.C. Division of Health records, 1984-1985 (Box 62)
      - Mental health exhibits (Box 62)
      - Brain scans, 9/30/1999 (Box 62)
      - Mental retardation tests and notes (Box 62)
      - Neuropsychological evaluation, 5/10/1991 (Box 62)
    - Transcript, 1/15/1996 (Box 62)
    - Motions for appropriate relief (Box 62)
    - Motion to recuse or disqualify, 01/1996 (Box 63)
    - Petition for writ of habeas corpus, 10/2003 (Box 63)
    - Transcript, 12/8/1986 (Box 63)
    - Drafts and releases, 2003 (Box 63)
    - Mental retardation documents (Box 63)
    - Mental health reference material (Box 63)
    - Facts (Box 63)
    - Trial transcript, 8/12/1991 - volume I, 2 folders (Box 63)
    - Trial transcript, 8/12/1991 - volume II, 2 folders (Box 63)
    - Trial transcript, 8/12/1991 - volume II (Box 64)
    - Trial transcript, 8/12/1991 - volume III (Box 64)
    - Trial transcript, 8/12/1991 - volume IV (Box 64)
    - Record on appeal (Box 64)
    - Transcript digest (Box 64)
    - Transcript, 01/15/1996 (Box 64)
    - Annotated DSM-IV mental health manual (Box 64)
    - Joint appendix files, 2 folders (Box 64)
    - Joint appendix files, 2 folders (Box 65)
    - Trial transcript, 10/7/2002 - volume II (Box 65)
    - Petition for involuntary commitment, 11/27/1984 (Box 65)
    - Issues and recommendations as to punishment, 3/30/1993 (Box 65)
    - USSC appendix to writ of certiorari (Box 65)
    - Attorney legal files (Box 65)
    - Mental health records (Box 65)
    - Published opinion, 1998 (Box 65)
    - Application for habeas corpus, 6/1999 (Box 65)
    - Proposed findings of fact, 9/1999 (Box 65)
    - Subpoenas for hearing in Wake Couty, 9/3/1999 (Box 65)
    - State's motion to lift stay, 6/1/2001 (Box 65)
    - Order granting discovery and setting deadline for claims, 10/11/2001 (Box 65)
    - Mitigating factors, 2 folders (Box 65)
    - Supplemental joint appendix, 12/1997 (Box 66)
    - Brief of petitioner, 4/1998 (Box 66)
    - Brief of appellee, 5/1998 (Box 66)
    - Brief of petitioner, 5/1998 (Box 66)
    - Evidence and verdicts (Box 66)
    - NCSC state's response to petition for writ of certiorari (Box 66)
    - Petition for writ of certiorari, 8/1999 (Box 66)
    - Motion for leave to proceed, 5/1999 (Box 66)
    - Flynn (Box 66)
    - WRAT-3 testing, 1/8/2002 (Box 66)
    - Statements, 1990 (Box 66)
    - Psychologist file (Box 66)
    - J.W. file (Box 66)
    - Dr. file (Box 66)
    - Evans Harrell (Box 66)
    - Research (Box 66)
    - Case law (Box 67)
    - PET scan (Box 67)
    - Medical records, 4 folders (Box 67)
    - DOC medical records (Box 67)
    - Attorney files, 2 folders (Box 67)
    - Notes and correspondence (Box 68)
    - Request for instructions - guilt/innocence phase (Box 68)
    - Discovery, 1986 (Box 68)
    - Court documents (Box 68)
    - Judgment and sentencing, 1991 (Box 68)
    - Research (Box 68)
    - Correspondence
      - Attorney correspondence, 1993 (Box 68)
      - Attorney correspondence with defendant, 2/6/1993 (Box 68)
      - Correspondence with the state (Box 68)
    - DOC medical documents (Box 68)
    - Jury selection, 1991 (Box 68)
    - Letters to Sallenger (Box 68)
    - Subpoenas (Box 68)
    - Jury materials, 1993 (Box 68)
    - Investigative information - resources (Box 68)
    - Notes (Box 68)
    - Defendant affidavit, 10/15/1995 (Box 68)
    - Potential state witnesses (Box 68)
    - Sample cases and statutes (Box 68)
    - Petition for rehearing, 12/21/1998 (Box 68)
    - Decision on petition for rehearing (Box 68)
    - Application for extension of time to file petition of certiorari, 10/1998 (Box 68)
    - Notice of caledaring (Box 68)
    - Petition for certiorari/supersedeas, motion for stay of execution (Box 68)
    - Published opinion - 4th Circuit, 12/1998 (Box 68)
    - Capital murder research (Box 68)
    - Attorney notes - jurors (Box 68)
    - Draft of MAR (Box 68)
    - Jury selection - rehab questions (Box 68)
    - Notes (Box 68)
    - Recusal issue (Box 68)
    - Research (Box 68)
    - Drs. files, 2 folders (Box 68)
    - Research and notes (Box 68)
    - CJA fee request paperwork (Box 68)
    - Research regarding rules and procedures (Box 68)
    - Post-conviction issues - CDPL seminar (Box 68)
    - Death penalty contacts (Box 69)
    - Notes, 3/18/1997 (Box 69)
    - DOC medical records, 5 folders (Box 69)
    - Motion to stay execution, 9/13/1999 (Box 69)
    - Motion to stay execution exhibits (Box 69)
    - Mental health/ability files, 2 folders (Box 69)
    - Mental health evidence, 2 folders (Box 70)
    - Trial transcript, 12/11/1986 (Box 70)
    - Stay of execution motions - other defendants (Box 70)
    - Attorney's notes (Box 70)
    - Jury list, 1991 (Box 70)
    - Uncategorized notes (Box 70)
    - Tarboro survey, 1993 (Box 70)
    - Orders (Box 70)
    - Motions (Box 70)
    - Attorney time sheets (Box 70)
    - Request for mitigating factors (Box 70)
    - Transcript digest (Box 70)
    - Subpoenas (Box 70)
    - List of exhibits (Box 70)
    - Student work product (Box 70)
    - USSC writ of certiorari, 10/2003 (Box 70)
    - Correspondence (Box 70)
    - Affidavits (Box 70)
    - Trial transcripts, 3/15/1993 (Box 71)
      - Volume I (Box 71)
      - Volume II (Box 71)
      - Volume III (Box 71)
      - Volume IV, 2 folders (Box 71)
      - Volume V (Box 71)
      - Volume VI (Box 71)
      - Volume VII (Box 71)
      - Volume VIII (Box 71)
      - Volume IX (Box 71)
    - Press (Box 72)
    - Orders (Box 72)
    - Arrest and release documents (Box 72)
    - Uncategorized trial transcripts (Box 72)
    - 2008-0117-Disk 007: Keel medical records (Box 72)
  - Gary Wayne Long, 1995-2003, 7 boxes
    Gary Long was indicted in February 1998 for the first-degree murder of his mother. Long was tried capitally and found guilty of first-degree murder on the basis of premeditation and deliberation. Following a capital sentencing proceeding, the jury recommended a sentence of death. Long's lawyers appealed the decision and on January 7, 2002 the North Carolina Supreme Court granted the defendant's request for a resentencing, citing absence of mitigating evidence at the initial trial. Long was resentenced to life in prison without parole on November 11, 2003.
    - 2008-0117-Disk 008: Gary Wayne Long data, 10/2/2002 (Box 72)
    - 2008-0117-Disk 003: Gary Wayne Long data (Box 72)
    - Copies of records, 2 folders (Box 72)
    - Medical and police records (Box 72)
    - D. Grey's bill (Box 72)
    - Expenses (Box 72)
    - Correspondence
      - T. King, 1999 (Box 72)
      - P. Green (Box 72)
      - Attorney (Box 72)
      - Church of Holy Family (CHF) (Box 72)
      - Client (Box 72)
    - Sample pleadings (Box 72)
    - Arrest report, 1998 (Box 72)
    - Case law summaries (Box 72)
    - Telephone records, 1995-1998 (Box 72)
    - Jury questions (Box 72)
    - Mitigation and consultation documents (Box 72)
    - Request for mitigating circumstances (Box 72)
    - Records/individuals consulted (Box 72)
    - Dorothea Dix hospital, 5/4/1999 (Box 72)
    - Dorothea Dix reports, 1998-1999 (Box 72)
    - Notes from D. Grey (Box 72)
    - DOC mental and medical health records (Box 72)
    - DOC mental and medical health records (Box 73)
    - Attorney notes (Box 73)
    - Interviews, 7 folders (Box 73)
    - Contact list (Box 73)
    - Crime scene report (Box 73)
    - Interviews, 7 folders (Box 73)
    - North Carolina Supreme Court (NCSC) opinion (Box 73)
    - Police reports (Box 73)
    - T. Thompson (Box 73)
    - Time of death information (Box 73)
    - Dr. Wilson (Box 73)
    - Long's biographical timeline (Box 73)
    - Non-statutory mitigating factors (Box 73)
    - Victim's medical records, 2 folders (Box 73)
    - Dr. Mason (Box 73)
    - Jury instructions (Box 73)
    - State discovery (Box 73)
    - Mitigation, 2 folders (Box 73)
    - Health records, 12 folders (Box 73)
    - Rowan County involuntary commitment (Box 74)
    - Chronological review of records (Box 74)
    - Disability under Social Security Act (Box 74)
    - Correspondence (Box 74)
    - Defendant's releases (Box 74)
    - Felony case report (Grey) (Box 74)
    - School records (Box 74)
    - Social history (Grey) (Box 74)
    - Interviews, 14 folders (Box 74)
    - Long's timeline (Box 74)
    - Employment (Box 74)
    - Mitigation themes - first trial (Box 74)
    - Correspondence
      - Client (Box 74)
      - Client - pre-trial (Box 74)
      - T. King (Box 74)
      - Kannapolis police department (Box 74)
      - Victim's family members (Box 74)
      - State Bureau of Investigation (SBI) (Box 74)
      - Trial attorneys (Box 74)
    - Autopsy report, 2 folders (Box 74)
    - Defendant's genogram (Box 74)
    - Medical files, 4 folders (Box 74)
    - MMPI data (defendant and victim), 2 folders (Box 74)
    - Releases (Grey) (Box 74)
    - Mitigating documents (Box 74)
    - Department of Corrections (DOC) death row roster, 2002 (Box 74)
    - Rowan County probation records (Box 74)
    - Salisbury Post clippings, 9/16/1999 (Box 74)
    - Crime scene report (Box 74)
    - Defense witness list (Box 74)
    - State's witness list (Box 74)
    - District attorney's (DA) trial notes (Box 74)
    - Evidence log (Box 74)
    - DA's order of witnesses (Box 74)
    - Jurors (Box 74)
    - Ambulance report (Box 74)
    - Priors (Box 74)
    - Pre-trial court orders (Box 74)
    - Rowan County Detention Center - inmate telephone numbers (Box 74)
    - Salisbury ENT clinic (Box 74)
    - Motions for expert funding (Box 74)
    - Expert payments (Box 74)
    - SBI lab reports (Box 74)
    - King - billing records (Box 74)
    - Victim's records, 4 folders (Box 74)
    - Kannapolis Police Department (KPD) files, 3 folders (Box 74)
    - Kannapolis Police Department (KPD) files, 2 folders (Box 75)
    - Doctors' files, 9 folders (Box 75)
    - List of KPD officers, 5/13/1999 (Box 75)
    - Interviews, 8 folders (Box 75)
    - Victim's death certificate (Box 75)
    - Time of death (Box 75)
    - Transfer order, 12/10/2002 (Box 75)
    - Transcript digest (Box 75)
    - T. Thompson - trial counsel (Box 75)
    - Motion to continue, 2002 (Box 75)
    - King - fee schedule (trial) (Box 75)
    - Correspondence, 4 folders (Box 75)
    - Jurors (Box 75)
    - Discovery motion, 2002 (Box 75)
    - Discovery order, 2002 (Box 75)
    - Defendant's criminal record (Box 75)
    - Assault of female charge, 1997 (Box 75)
    - Statute of limitations (Box 75)
    - Transfer motion, 10/31/2002 (Box 75)
    - State v. Hayes (Box 75)
    - K. Rose - field notes (Box 75)
    - Pro hac vice motion, 10/18/2002 (Box 75)
    - Pro hac vice order (Box 75)
    - Preservation motion (Box 75)
    - Motion for extension of time, 1/13/2003 (Box 75)
    - Assignment of counsel, 2 folders (Box 75)
    - Motion to transport for evaluation (Box 75)
    - NCSC opinion - direct appeal, 12/18/2001 (Box 75)
    - Motion for appropriate relief (MAR) (Box 75)
    - Testimony of Officer Ballard, 9/6/1999 (Box 75)
    - Defense opening statement, 9/6/1999 (Box 75)
    - Transcripts (Box 76)
      - Transcript I(a), 9/7/1999 (Box 76)
      - Transcript II, 9/6/1999 (Box 76)
      - Rule 24 hearing, 3/17/1998 (Box 76)
      - Arraignment, 4/8/1998 (Box 76)
      - Motion, 5/3/1999 (Box 76)
      - Motion, 8/20/1999 (Box 76)
      - Competency hearing, 9/2/1999 (Box 76)
      - Volume I, 9/7 through 9/10/1999, 3 folders (Box 76)
    - Trial notebook, 2 folders (Box 76)
    - Trial notebook uncategorized (Box 76)
    - Trial notebook (Box 77)
    - T. Thompson's files, 3 folders (Box 77)
    - Jury questionnaire (Box 77)
    - Mitigation notebook #1 (Grey's), 2 folders (Box 77)
    - Mitigation notebook #2 (Box 77)
    - Mitigation notebook #2 (Box 78)
    - Notebook on jury (Box 78)
    - P. Green's files, 2 folders (Box 78)
    - Trial transcript - volume III, 9/14/1999, 2 folders (Box 78)
    - Excerpts from DA's argument (Box 78)
    - Defense attorney's closing (Box 78)
    - Uncategorized legal documents (Box 78)
    - Documents obtained by PMG during appeal, 1999; 2 folders (Box 132)
    - Tom Thompson's trial notebook, 1998-1999; 4 folders (Box 132)
    - Tom Thompson's files, 1949-1998; 3 folders (Box 132)
    - Trial transcript, 1998-1999; 4 folders (Box 132)
    - Correspondence, notes, 2002; undated (Box 132)
    - DA's discovery, 1998-1999; 3 folders (Box 132)
  - James Lewis Martin, Jr., 1980-1998, 6 boxes
    James Martin was tried and sentenced to death for a double murder in Montgomery County, Alabama. His capital-murder conviction and death sentence followed a trial proceeding in which the prosecution failed to disclose several pieces of material evidence. The Alabama Court of Appeals found that there was a reasonable probability that disclosure of the suppressed evidence would have produced a different result at Martin's trial. Martin subsequently pled guilty to two counts of murder and was sentenced to life in prison.
    - Case law and research material, 4 folders (Box 79)
    - Case law, 4 folders (Box 79)
    - Case law, 5 folders (Box 80)
    - Hypnosis, 2 folders (Box 80)
    - Defendant's family background information (Box 80)
    - Defendant's background information (Box 80)
    - DHR health records (Box 80)
    - Depositions and interviews, 11 folders (Box 81)
    - Circuit court documents (Box 81)
    - Uncategorized legal documents (Box 81)